# **Ankur Ramoliya**

Girivar Residency, Ahmedabad Vastral 382418, / Ramoliya.ankur@gmail.com / +919825212013

**Profile Statement:** An IT professional with 10 Years of experience in handling various projects related to Server and Network Management, considerable standardizations in IT operations to reduce Time from the processes & strengthen daily work management. People Management, Strong communication, Presentation & Analytical Skills are my core strengths. Aditya Birla Group, CMS, Techindia infosoution, Hitachi System Micro Clinic, PCS, Wipro are major learning organizations of my portfolio.

## **Employment History:**

• Aditya Birla Grasim

**Team Lead** 

Veraval Gujarat, From: May 2012 to April 2019.

Torrent Power (Project Transfer)

**Team Lead** 

Ahmedabad Gujarat, From: May 2019 to Nov 2020.

• Hi Tech informatic Pvt. Ltd.

**System Admin** 

Ahmedabad Gujarat, From: Nov 2020 to Nov 2021...

• GTPL Hathway Pvt. Ltd.

System Admin (A.M)

Ahmedabad Gujarat, From: Dec 2021 to Nov 2022

Odoo Indian Pvt Ltd.

**System Admin** 

Ahmedabad Gujarat, From: Dec 2021 to Nov Cont...

### Responsibilities:

- Team Handling, Plant and remote location.
- Interviewing and IT induction Training.
- Manage the AMC and renewal all type of IT equipment
- Responsible for the purchase of hardware component from reliable sources and effective prices.
- Providing technical support to the engineers working in field.
- Manage the L2/L3 Switch on out the environment.
- Inventory and daily, weekly, and monthly reports.
- Request such as backup, permissions changes, patch application and testing of software
- Manage Co-ordination with Vendor for Multi-Function Printer, Desktop, Laptop, Server Production Related Software and other equipment

- Performs system backups and recovery for clients as per their requests.
- Perform system admin activities to include administrative functions in active directory,
- Network printer, scanner, Attendance machine and digital signature token.
- Experience of with an ITIL Process and SLA
- Managing Active Directory, Creating and managing user account, providing user's specific rights and Securities.
- Providing 24X7 support to mission critical equipment's with various Departments.
- Providing assistance to users through remote desktop.
- Schedule and monitoring all types of IT Device Preventive Maintenance
- Monitoring Internal Hardware Spare transaction and maintaining the inventory on periodic basis.
- Generating monthly and weekly reports on a regular basis for better systems management
- Ensuring to gather data from all relevant stakeholders in order to maintain better databases.
- Taking corrective feedback from all the clients as well as running regular survey for better IT Systems.
- Team management and Data management.
- Network, Firewall, and router
- when required, Data, access logs storage and retrieval
- Manage the license like Server, office, adobe, Auto cad etc.
- CCTV and Radar system mgmt.

#### Skill

- Management & Repost
- Installation and manage servers
- Windows, Linux servers Troubleshooting
- Backup and Restore Mgmt.

- IT equipment Hardware and software configuration and budget and planning.
- Active Directory and Group Policy
- Mg Enterprise Network Management.
- Technical document, Policy, SLA and SOP

•

## **Projects**

- Office 365 Migration
- Created Survey Different Department by Survey Monkey Site
- Hug number of (5000+) DT, LT, Printer, and other IT and network devices upgradation and user management
- Symantec to TrendMicro Antivirus Project Trend micro encryption and user data, Seqrite also.
- Network Switch upgradation, WIFI network upgradation.
- Indoor Outdoor LED Project.

# **Talent Acquisition**

- Knowledge about safety, Kaizen, and 5S Systems.
- Experience RAID, and Veeam and Commvault backup application.
- Mount/dismount servers on Racks, ADD/Remove Hardware parts from the servers.
- Backup and Recovery through Tap Drive with backup tool Application.
- Server and network hardware configuration and POA and Delivered to User.
- Ready to new server virtual as well physical and configure same as user requirement.
- Install and manage and physical server.
- Involves IT team members in planning
- Adaptable with frequently changing requirements
- Has excellent communication skills
- Basic troubleshooting knowledge of Linux
- Knowledge networking, firewall, router, and switch etc.
- Managed systems installations and implementations.
- Managing IT assets Data and reporting Metadata to Management.
- Drafted reports and worked with the management team.
- Knowledge of Laptop, desktop, Workstation, server, troubleshooting
- Troubleshooting Remotely via RDP and VNC. Identify diagnoses and resolves Issues.
- Following standards & procedures defined by the global IT group with ticketing system
- Install and Troubleshooting Windows 98/XP, 7,8, 10 and server OS Prompt support and Action for Top/Management level users.
- Server management is a supporting responsibility, and would be responsible for installing, maintaining (PC & Laptops/I-Pad/MacBook, Linux, Other custom OS) and upgrading software.
- Recommend and perform upgrades on hardware and software systems to ensure longevity.
- HDD media add/remove from servers and provide support from Data Center & remote locations.

### **Education:**

- 10<sup>th</sup> S.S.C in Gujarat university
- 12<sup>th</sup> H.S.C in Gujarat university
- B.C.A in Jaipur National University
- MCSA Is Running (Microsoft Certification)

## **Personal Details:**

Name: Ankur V. Ramoliya

Father Name: Vallabhbhai Mohanbhai Ramoliya

Marital Status: Married

Permanent Address: At. Ambhlash-Gir, Ta. Talala-Gir,

Dis. Girsomanth 362150.

Date:	nkur	Ramoli	y
-------	------	--------	---